hey hey what's up my friend so if you're
looking at me right now and thinking man
right now you look a little bit
different now what's going on man yeah
so so here's the truth right I'm
actually standing up as I'm shooting
this video here right so uh my equipment
somehow got a little bit of upgrade my
my desk actually my desk all along it
could you know uh rise up right but I
didn't use that feature until now
because previously my cable was too
short you know I tried to bring my
desktop higher the cable would kind of
like snap I lost my power how silly I
was right back then I got this table
with this feature but my cable is too
short so now that I have a longer cable
right yeah I can you know get this
standing desk to move up I can speak
through the mic look at this webcam and
you know I'm actually standing and I
think I feel more energetic right while
while shooting this video it's you know
it's it's yeah so anyway uh in this
video over here today uh I want to share
with you my trading results and and for
those of you who have followed me for
while now you know that I actually am
not very you know comfortable you know
always you know flashing my trading
results my p&l because I I don't want
you know give off the wrong expectation
I don't want to be assoc associated with
the type of Traders know it's always you
know showing off how much profits is
made look at my
Lamborghini that's not me right but
sometimes I do get it that for for
others right who have not seen your
results they may not you know really
think that you can trade the market it's
just some random you know uh guy on the
internet spouting nonsense they have to
you know differentiate yourself from
someone who trades in someone who
doesn't trade so for example this is one
of the the command that I I get right I
think every few weeks or few months you
know someone will ask a question like
this right uh this is from love cash
right show p&l statement yeah are you
really a Trader or just a YouTuber so
when I see you know statements like
this my first thought that comes into my
mind is that why does it have to be
mutually exclusive do you go to someone
and say are you a father or are you an
employee well why can't you be an
employee and father at the same time why
can't you be a someone who creates
content for YouTube and be a Trader at
the same time why can't you be even you
know someone who sell courses and be a
Trader at the same time and in fact I'm
old right I do multiple things I wear
multiple heads I even I'm even nowadays
maybe even a podcaster I like to
interview Traders and you know people
with interesting background stories why
why do you have to you know associate
people with just one specific uh
identity yeah so I wear multiple heads
right so yeah that's that's me right I
like it that way I like you know novel
things you know trying different things
here and there and we have a comment
from fire Jet right uh pretty nice guy
right he tell them to you know justy
simply search uh my past YouTube channel
you can pretty much find a p&l statement
so so one thing that you know really I
think this kind of brings me to to my
point right you know often people ask me
questions you know leave a feedback and
my most direct answer would be you know
if you have a question for me chances
are that question you know other Traders
have asked me previously I do a search
on my YouTube channel on my website
trading rom.com and you might you could
probably find a very detailed answer
maybe in the form of a video or a blog
post format yeah on the comment section
I probably could just reply you know a
few sentences and that's it there's
really not much depth that my reply can
give you compared to some of my older
videos and blog post that I've done so
try doing a search for that and see if
I've you know created content on the
topic that you're looking for if there
isn't right you know then I will do my
best you know to help uh reply you know
if I do see your question and I feel I
feel that I can add value to your
question yeah but if not you know do a
quick search YouTube and my website is
pretty much the first thing that you
want to do first yeah so anyway uh
moving on right let's uh look at uh uh
my trading results right that you're
probably in on this video video here for
so uh today right I trade multiple
trading strategies across different
markets and and yeah for this particular
strategy or system if you want to call
it this is a trading system that trades
the the stock market you can see this
system up about 21% over the last one
year you can see over here this is my
Interactive Broker account statement and
one thing to highlight is
that almost every profitable trading
strategy system that I come across it's
not going to go up in one straight line
it's not like some of this Forex robot
that you subscribe to where the equity
curve just go right just one straight
line you know no pullback or whatsoever
no any trading strategy that actually
works in the long run that will be you
know it's like it'll be like in an
uptrend he goes out makes a pullback
goes out makes a pullback right and
pretty much something like this yeah I
don't claim to make money every week
every day or every month I have losing
months period as you can see in this
Equity curve over here but in the long
run when you have an age when you have a
proven trading system that works your
Equity curve could look something like
this maybe yours could be better right
where your Equity curve is smoother you
know and what not so for this particular
trading uh system let me just give you a
quick overview the idea behind this
system that I used to trade right is
pretty much identify stocks right that
are in an uptrend I wait for a pullback
over here I buy and then when there's a
bounce a rally I sell you can see the
concept is very simple buy the pullback
sell the rally apply this in stocks that
are trending or already in an uptrend
that's it yeah and the other strategy
right over here this is another account
that I have you know Interactive Broker
allows you to have multiple sub accounts
so this is the second one this one over
here you can see this past one year up
about close to 60% so for this
particular strategy or system if going
to call it I pretty much identify stocks
that are already sort of like uh
trending higher or just broke out let me
see if I can get this blank screen okay
so pretty much for the second system
right I identify stocks that already
trending up higher I buy they I Look to
write the trend up higher all the way
until you show signs of reversal and
then I sell so for this second system
right it's uh you can see over here you
might be wondering man right you know
why why is the return so high compared
to the first one so there's a there's a
catch to this right this particular
system right it is higher risk so it say
higher return but it has higher risk
this means the draw down is larger as
well so this means when the market moves
against me I could give up you know
quite a huge chunk of open profits and
the reason why I trade multiple trading
system is
because I have no idea you know how the
market condition is going to be like
let's say next year or two years later
so this is why I trade multiple systems
that can take advantage of different
market conditions so let's say it's a
bare Market guess what I will have a
system a strategy that will do well in a
bare Market if the market is range of
bullish guess what I have systems that
also do well in markets which are
ranging or bullish so this is why I
trade multiple trading system and it's a
concept I learned from you know other
veteran Traders like you know Lawrence
Ben stop who else I learned from Cesar
Alvarez Nick R all these veteran Traders
right they pretty much talk about this
concept and it really resonates a lot
with me yeah
so to kind of like share with you some
of the lessons I learned over you know
the last few months in trading so some
of the recent lessons right I have many
lessons you know throughout my trading
career if I going to share all this
video be more than an hour long but just
one of the recent lessons I learned is
that you know
always I'm always a student of the
markets right so just quick a quick kind
of like rundown to my own trading career
SL history I started off with you know
trading indicators right you know
because it's sexy right you know you
look for this line to cross below this
line you sell cross up you buy and stuff
like that it's the easiest thing to kind
of like get hooked into trading and make
you think that that's all trading there
is to it right and in fact that that
could actually work right if you do the
the if you back test it there are
certain strategies could could work
right when just two line cross each
other and on certain markets yeah so I
started off with indicators then I move
on to to chart patterns you know the
classical chart patterns the more
complicated complex one like harmonic
patterns then I move on to price action
trading then that's where uh shortly
after that also got involved with Trend
following they got involved with systems
trading multiple trading systems they
got you know trading systems on the
intraday Market basis that have to start
you know develop a API to run this uh
intraday trading systems and now I'm
considering know moving to the crypto
markets you know for more opportunities
you can see that my trading career it's
it's really it's it's never ending
because after you learn one thing after
you master one thing or maybe after you
realize this thing is not for you you
move on to the next and that's what I
keep doing I learn one thing I embrace
it if it works for me I keep it and then
I move on to the next and and really I'm
always a student of the market so one of
the So-Cal struggles that I'm facing
right now is uh like I want to move into
the crypto markets but I find it to I
have difficulty finding you know crypto
data clean proper crypto data that fits
with my back testing software which is
Army broker so I'm still currently
finding a solution for it another of my
struggles right now is that I I do run
uh couple of intraday trading systems
and I close the positions before the
endend of the day before the market
closes I I'm in Asia I'm not going to
wake up at 4:00 a.m. to close my
position so I'm trying to have this API
to close the right positions and somehow
or rather the API is still buggy so all
this has been going on and you can see
really I'm you know still a student
right I'm always know learning figuring
out new things each day and I find that
trading is actually kind of like similar
to to entrepreneurship you must have
this curiosity this hunger to always try
and test new things because because you
never know you know what could happen so
this is my own reflection over the last
few months and I find that yeah you know
you always got to be a student of the
markets it started off with you know
passion curiosity interest and now as
I'm scaling up right you know I got to
kind of like way the pros and cons my
time is limited which of the things I
tackle right now is the lowest hanging
fruit and I want to go for that yeah and
uh before I end off I think uh Q&A here
so I think some another question that I
get Al this one which is actually a
quote right that I I I I that came to my
mind recently right basically talking
about how you need to have an age in the
markets yeah and once you have an age
discipline becomes a lot easier and then
some people I don't watch WWE but
clearly I think it's a character in WWE
and a couple of you are asking me know
know what is an H again I think if you
do a search on my YouTube in my blog
post you probably can find an answer so
I'm since I'm shooting this video I want
to explain right so an H is simply
something right
that you do repeatedly over time right
that yields a positive result for
example a casino they have a
mathematical age over the players
because the game is riged in such a way
where the probabilities right is in
favor of the casino regardless of what
games you play yeah so that's the age of
a casino uh for high frequency trading
firms right their age is the speed right
they can place order so quickly right in
enough they trade so fast that you know
it's something that retail Traders we
can't even do because we're not as fast
as this algorithm so their age is
largely speed so if you ask me for
retail Traders your age would mainly be
at least from based on what I see what I
know right mathematical age and
emotional age so let me explain right so
so for the couple of trading systems I
shared with you earlier they are both
based on math and logic SL emotion if
you want to call it like for example the
the trend following strategy I Shar with
you earlier why is there an age because
when price just breaks out to new High
many traders who are you know
inexperience you know not good at this
you think oh man R the market is so high
it's time to sell and then I buy right
and guess what sometimes when you buy it
goes even higher so I can write this
trend up higher right profiting this
longterm uptrend where all these other
Traders are on the sidelines or even
shorting it so this is where you know
emotionally right I find that uh
sorry emotionally that trading strategy
can be quite difficult to trade because
you're buying high and selling low right
buying High to sell higher sell low and
cover lower so same thing for the mean
reversion trading system or rather the
pullback trading system that I Shar with
you earlier when the market makes a
sudden Spike down a pullback many
Traders will freak out oh man it's a
reversal you know World War II but
people like me are come in I'll buy the
pullback I'll buy the spike down in the
hopes that the market will bounce up
higher and then I can sell on the rally
so I'm taking advantage of this
emotional aspects of other Traders right
and that is my age and I can also
quantify based on the back testing work
that I have done so anyway if you want
to you want to learn more on how you can
go about finding your own age in the
markets right uh I've actually written
this guide over here called the
essential guide to systems trading I'll
share with you how you can go about
finding your own age in markets how to
develop your own trading strength IES
your own systems I believe in that gu I
even share with you a simple Trend
following system that works right back
by data so if you want to learn more
it's all in this uh this guide over here
right can grab a copy just click this
orange button enter email address and
I'll send it to you for free so with
that it right uh wish you all Good Luck
Good trading have a great week ahead and
I will talk to you soon